<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Gula</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Gula</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 17:22:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Osteoradionecrosis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteoradionecrosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 17:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/osteoradionecrosis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Osteoradionecrosis (ORN)&lt;/strong&gt; is to a delayed radiation injury characterised by bone necrosis and failure of wound healing for at least 3-6 months, may result from radiotherapy alone or in combination with a mechanical insult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The condition most often occurs after radiotherapy (iatrogenic) and might be referred to as post-radiotherapy osteonecrosis, ocurring on average 2-4 years after completing the therapy with an incidence of 3%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two complementary theories exist to describe the pathogenesis:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cheilitis Granulomatosa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cheilitis-granulomatosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 16:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cheilitis-granulomatosa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cheilitis granulomatosa (CG)&lt;/strong&gt;: rare granulomatous disorder, recurrent firm swelling of one or both lips. In isolation, it&amp;rsquo;s called cheilitis granulomatosa of Miescher (CGM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Melkersson-Rosenthal syndrome (MRS)&lt;/strong&gt;: classical triad of recurrent or persistent orofacial edema, plicated/fissured tongue (lingua plicata), and relapsing peripheral facial nerve paralysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orofacial granulomatosis: a syndrome grouping noninfectious and nonnecrotizing granulomatous involvement of the lips, oral cavity, and face, it includes CG and MRS, sarcoidosis, and Crohn&amp;rsquo;s disease, although the latter 2 are sometimes excluded to make the classification specific to conditions with no systemic involvement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete triad is uncommon and may be observed in 25% to 33% of patients, even then the symptoms rarely appear simultaneously, and long intervals between the occurrence of paralysis and the first swelling have been reported. The disease evolves by flare-ups, yet permanent edema of the lips, and sometimes of the face, can be observed gradually developing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frey&#39;s Syndrome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/freys-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 16:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/freys-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frey syndrome&lt;/strong&gt; (Baillarger’s syndrome, auriculotemporal syndrome, Dupuy syndrome, gustatory hyperhidrosis) occurs due to aberrant reinnervation following injury to the auriculotemporal nerve, most often following parotidectomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because nerve regeneration takes time, presentation generally occurs 6 to 18 months after surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While not lethal, it can significantly reduce patients&amp;rsquo; quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The published incidence of Frey syndrome after parotidectomy varies from 4% to 96%. The wide range of rates reported in the literature reflects great heterogeneity of symptom severity, reporting, and diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
